<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<class name="CobbAPIString">
   <blurb>
      Functions for working with Papyrus strings. Unlike the functions 
      offered by SKSE, these are generally UTF-8-aware.
   </blurb>
   <description>
      <p>
         These functions can be used to work with Papyrus strings. Unlike the functions offered 
         by SKSE, these are generally UTF-8-aware.
      </p>
      <h2>An overview of how computers store text</h2>
      <p>
         In order to avoid ambiguity, I would prefer to document things using the most precise 
         terminology possible, but much of this terminology isn't known to people who don't 
         explicitly do "serious" text programming. I had to do some learning myself in order to 
         offer as much functionality as I wanted to. As such, here's a "brief" primer on how 
         computers store text.
      </p>
      <p>
         Computers can only work with numeric data, so every symbol that a piece of text may 
         contain must be represented using a number, or "code point." The oldest surviving 
         system for this is ASCII (American Standard Code for Information Interchange), which 
         was introduced in 1963. In this system, every single glyph is represented with a 
         single byte, and so up to 256 glyphs (including a string terminator and other control 
         codes) can be represented. ASCII only defined 128 glyphs, all focused on English text, 
         leaving the last 128 glyphs undefined.
      </p>
      <p>
         As such, non-English text could only be represented in alternate encodings. Because 
         virtually all programming is done in English, these encodings are typically supersets 
         of ASCII. For languages that have large numbers of glyphs, such as Chinese, Japanese, 
         Korean, and Vietnamese, these encodings often have to use multiple bytes for some or 
         all glyphs.
      </p>
      <p>
         In 1991, the Unicode standard was published. It uses multiple bytes for all glyphs in 
         order to maximize its coverage and support as many languages and scripts as possible, 
         but there are alternate encodings (such as UTF-8) that are designed to compress Unicode 
         text whenever possible, with a focus on representing ASCII as compactly as possible 
         (given that markup and program code, invisible to a user, will be in ASCII).
      </p>
      <p>
         Unicode has nuances that are largely invisible to native English-speaking programmers, 
         who won't encounter or have to work with foreign-language text unless they put 
         themselves in situations where they may encounter it. Native English-speaking 
         programmers are used to the assumptions that one glyph will be represented one way 
         using one byte, and all of those assumptions fall apart when using Unicode and UTF-8.
      </p>
      <p>
         A single glyph can be represented using multiple code point sequences: Unicode offers 
         better ways of representing glyphs that have diacritics, but it also retains older 
         representations for backward compatibility's sake. Moreover, a single code point will 
         be multiple bytes in Unicode; in UTF-8, ASCII code points are single-byte while all 
         other code points are multi-byte (with higher code points requiring more bytes).
      </p>
      <p>
         The string functions offered by CobbAPI are Unicode-aware, and the documentation will 
         reflect this: string lengths, character comparisons, and more are done on the basis of 
         code points, not glyphs or bytes.
      </p>
      <h2>String handling in Papyrus</h2>
      <p>
         When Papyrus strings are written to ESP and ESM files, they are always written in 
         UTF-8, regardless of the language in use by a mod author's system. I assume that UTF-8 
         is also used for Papyrus strings at run-time. (I'm not sure what would happen to string 
         constants in a script, though; does the Papyrus Compiler treat all files as UTF-8?)
      </p>
      <p>
         It's worth noting that non-Papyrus strings are not guaranteed to use UTF-8. In Skyrim 
         Classic, the text encoding used by the rest of the game varies from language to 
         language. Worse, ESP and ESM files don't contain any metadata identifying their 
         language or their encoding. As such, Papyrus functions that pull strings from game 
         data (such as getters for editor IDs and actors' names) will generally return data in 
         an unknown encoding, which may or may not be UTF-8.
      </p>
      <p>
         Papyrus strings are stored case-insensitively according to the C/POSIX locale (which 
         determines what characters are considered "letters" with uppercase and lowercase 
         forms). As such, the following glyphs, and only the following glyphs, are considered 
         interchangeable:
      </p>
      <table class="sideways">
         <tbody>
            <tr>
               <th>Uppercase</th>
               <td>A</td>
               <td>B</td>
               <td>C</td>
               <td>D</td>
               <td>E</td>
               <td>F</td>
               <td>G</td>
               <td>H</td>
               <td>I</td>
               <td>J</td>
               <td>K</td>
               <td>L</td>
               <td>M</td>
               <td>N</td>
               <td>O</td>
               <td>P</td>
               <td>Q</td>
               <td>R</td>
               <td>S</td>
               <td>T</td>
               <td>U</td>
               <td>V</td>
               <td>W</td>
               <td>X</td>
               <td>Y</td>
               <td>Z</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
               <th>Lowercase</th>
               <td>a</td>
               <td>b</td>
               <td>c</td>
               <td>d</td>
               <td>e</td>
               <td>f</td>
               <td>g</td>
               <td>h</td>
               <td>i</td>
               <td>j</td>
               <td>k</td>
               <td>l</td>
               <td>m</td>
               <td>n</td>
               <td>o</td>
               <td>p</td>
               <td>q</td>
               <td>r</td>
               <td>s</td>
               <td>t</td>
               <td>u</td>
               <td>v</td>
               <td>w</td>
               <td>x</td>
               <td>y</td>
               <td>z</td>
            </tr>
         </tbody>
      </table>
      <p>
         The game handles case-insensitivity byte by byte, so an accented letter will be 
         handled differently depending on whether it is a single code point or two (a 
         non-accented letter followed by an accent diacritic).
      </p>
      <p>
         If you specify two different strings that are identical save for case, the game will 
         use the first variant to load. The catch is that this applies across most or all of the 
         game engine, not just within Papyrus. In an English game, it is impossible to set a 
         Papyrus string variable to "dog" because there is already an in-game Race form named 
         "Dog", and so "Dog" was the first variant of the string to load. Similarly, trying to 
         set a string to "oBjEcTreferenCE" will always yield "ObjectReference" instead.
      </p>
   </description>
   <methods>
      <method name="BinaryToInt32" returns="Int">
         <args>
            <arg type="String" name="asString">
               A string representing a binary number, e.g. <code>"0010"</code> or 
               <code>"10101010"</code>.
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Converts a stringified binary number to an integer.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function parses <var>asString</var> in search of a valid binary  
               number, and returns either the found number or zero. Separators, such as 
               decimal points and commas, are not allowed; the function works by searching 
               for the first byte representing ASCII "0" or "1", and stopping at the first 
               byte after that that isn't an ASCII "0" or "1".
            </p>
         </description>
         <example-data>
            <comment>
               This call would return 18:
            </comment>
            <call return-var="iNumber">
               <arg value="10010" />
            </call>
         </example-data>
         <related type="method" name="HexToInt32" />
         <related type="method" name="ToBinary" />
         <related type="method" name="ToHex" />
      </method>
      <method name="CPLength" returns="Int">
         <args>
            <arg type="String" name="asString" />
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Returns a string's length in code points.
         </blurb>
         <example-data>
            <comment>
               This call would return 6:
            </comment>
            <call return-var="iLength">
               <arg value="一周有七天。" /> <!-- "There are seven days in a week." -->
            </call>
            <comment>
               SKSE's length getter would return 18 &#8212; the number of bytes.
               
               (The Chinese phrase means, "There are seven days in a week.")
            </comment>
         </example-data>
      </method>
      <method name="HexToInt32" returns="Int">
         <args>
            <arg type="String" name="asString">
               A string representing a hexadecimal number, e.g. <code>"0x0012"</code> or 
               <code>"0xDEADBEEF"</code>.
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Converts a stringified hexadecimal number to an integer.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function parses <var>asString</var> in search of a valid hexadecimal 
               number, and returns either the found number or zero. Separators, such as 
               decimal points and commas, are not allowed; the function works by searching 
               for the first byte representing a valid digit, and continuing until it 
               finds a byte that does not represent a valid digit.
            </p>
         </description>
         <example-data>
            <comment>
               A code example for a SkyUI MCM that lets you enter a form ID.
            </comment>
            <raw>
Form Property pkSelectedForm = None Auto Hidden
;
Event OnInputAcceptST(String asInput)
   pkSelectedForm = None
   ;
   Int iInput = CobbAPIString.HexToInt32(asInput)
   If iInput
      pkSelectedForm = Game.GetFormEx(iInput)
   EndIf
EndEvent
            </raw>
         </example-data>
         <related type="method" name="BinaryToInt32" />
         <related type="method" name="ToBinary" />
         <related type="method" name="ToHex" />
      </method>
      <method name="NaturalCompare_ASCII" returns="Int">
         <args>
            <arg type="String" name="a" />
            <arg type="String" name="b" />
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Perform a "natural" comparison on two strings.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function performs a "natural" comparison on two strings, to indicate 
               whether one would sort above the other. If <var>a</var> would sort below 
               <var>b</var>, this function returns -1; if it would sort above <var>b</var>, 
               this function returns 1; and if the two strings have the same natural sort 
               order, this function returns 0.
            </p>
            <p>
               When dealing with ASCII, the difference between a "natural" or alphabetical sort, 
               and an "ASCIIbetical" sort, are as follows:
            </p>
            <table class="narrow">
               <thead>
                  <tr>
                     <th>ASCIIbetical</th>
                     <th>Alphabetical</th>
                  </tr>
               </thead>
               <tbody>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z1</td>
                     <td>z1</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z10</td>
                     <td>z2</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z11</td>
                     <td>z3</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z12</td>
                     <td>z4</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z13</td>
                     <td>z5</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z2</td>
                     <td>z6</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z3</td>
                     <td>z7</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z4</td>
                     <td>z8</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z5</td>
                     <td>z9</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z6</td>
                     <td>z10</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z7</td>
                     <td>z11</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z8</td>
                     <td>z12</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                     <td>z9</td>
                     <td>z13</td>
                  </tr>
               </tbody>
            </table>
            <p>
               The comparison works by comparing code points until a numeric digit is found in 
               the same place in both strings. Once digits are found, we instead parse the digits 
               into numbers, and then compare the numbers.
            </p>
         </description>
         <related type="method" name="NaturalSort_ASCII" />
         <related type="method" name="NaturalSortPairInt_ASCII" />
         <related type="method" name="NaturalSortPairForm_ASCII" />
      </method>
      <method name="NaturalSort_ASCII" returns="Int">
         <args>
            <arg type="String[]" name="asStrings" />
            <arg type="Bool" name="abDescending" default="False">
               If this argument is True, then the strings will be sorted in descending 
               order (i.e. Z to A).
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Performs a "natural" sort on an array of strings.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function creates a copy of <var>asStrings</var>, performs a "natural" sort 
               on the copy, and then returns the copy.
            </p>
            <p>
               Refer to the documentation for NaturalCompare_ASCII to better understand 
               exactly how strings are sorted.
            </p>
         </description>
         <related type="method" name="NaturalCompare_ASCII" />
         <related type="method" name="NaturalSortPairInt_ASCII" />
         <related type="method" name="NaturalSortPairForm_ASCII" />
      </method>
      <method name="NaturalSortPairForm_ASCII" returns="Int">
         <args>
            <arg type="String[]" name="asStrings" />
            <arg type="Bool" name="abDescending" default="False">
               If this argument is True, then the strings will be sorted in descending 
               order (i.e. Z to A).
            </arg>
            <arg type="Form[]" name="axSecond" />
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Performs a "natural" sort on an array of strings, and on a matching array.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function creates a copy of <var>asStrings</var>, performs a "natural" sort 
               on the copy, and then returns the copy. The <var>axSecond</var> array is modified 
               directly (<em>not</em> copied), such that its elements still match those of the 
               string array.
            </p>
            <p>
               Refer to the documentation for NaturalCompare_ASCII to better understand 
               exactly how strings are sorted.
            </p>
         </description>
         <example-data>
            <comment>
               Get a list of all LightingTemplates, and then sort that list by their EditorIDs.
            </comment>
            <raw>
Form[]   kLightingTemplates = CobbAPILightingTemplate.GetAllForms()
String[] sEditorIDs         = CobbAPIForm.GetEditorIDs(kLightingTemplates)
sEditorIDs = CobbAPIString.NaturalSortPairForm_ASCII(sEditorIDs, False, kLightingTemplates)
            </raw>
            <comment>
               sEditorIDs[i] == the editor ID for kLightingTemplates[i], but now they're sorted.
            </comment>
         </example-data>
         <related type="method" name="NaturalCompare_ASCII" />
         <related type="method" name="NaturalSort_ASCII" />
         <related type="method" name="NaturalSortPairInt_ASCII" />
      </method>
      <method name="NaturalSortPairInt_ASCII" returns="Int">
         <args>
            <arg type="String[]" name="asStrings" />
            <arg type="Bool" name="abDescending" default="False">
               If this argument is True, then the strings will be sorted in descending 
               order (i.e. Z to A).
            </arg>
            <arg type="Int[]" name="axSecond" />
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Performs a "natural" sort on an array of strings, and on a matching array.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function creates a copy of <var>asStrings</var>, performs a "natural" sort 
               on the copy, and then returns the copy. The <var>axSecond</var> array is modified 
               directly (<em>not</em> copied), such that its elements still match those of the 
               string array.
            </p>
            <p>
               Refer to the documentation for NaturalCompare_ASCII to better understand 
               exactly how strings are sorted.
            </p>
         </description>
         <related type="method" name="NaturalCompare_ASCII" />
         <related type="method" name="NaturalSort_ASCII" />
         <related type="method" name="NaturalSortPairForm_ASCII" />
      </method>
      <method name="RegexMatch" returns="String[]">
         <args>
            <arg type="String" name="asHaystack">
               The string to search for matches.
            </arg>
            <arg type="String" name="asRegex">
               The regular expression to use. Regexes are in JavaScript format, but 
               without slashes as delimiters or trailing flags. Make sure to escape 
               any backslashes that appear in your regex.
            </arg>
            <arg type="String" name="asCaseSentinel">
               A string used to guard against Papyrus mangling the capitalization of characters 
               in the regex. This string must have the same number of code points as the regex 
               string. Any code point that should be lowercase in the regex should be a '0' in 
               this string; code points that should be uppercase in the regex should be '1' in 
               this string. code points that aren't case-insensitive letters can be represented 
               in this string using any other glyph. Make sure not to get confused by escaped 
               backslashes in the regex.
            </arg>
            <arg type="Bool" name="abWholeStringMustMatch" />
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Performs a regular expression match on a string.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function performs a regular expression match on a string and returns an 
               array of the results.
            </p>
         </description>
         <example-data>
            <comment>
               Find all three-letter words.
            </comment>
            <call return-var="sMatches" line-breaks="yes">
               <arg value="The cat and the dog are friends." />
               <arg value="(?:^|\W)(\w\w\w)(?:$|\W)" />
               <arg value="------1---1-1-1-------1-" />
               <arg value="False" />
            </call>
         </example-data>
         <related type="method" name="RegexReplace" />
         <related type="method" name="RegexSearch" />
      </method>
      <method name="RegexReplace" returns="String">
         <args>
            <arg type="String" name="asHaystack">
               The string to search for matches.
            </arg>
            <arg type="String" name="asRegex">
               The regular expression to use. Regexes are in JavaScript format, but 
               without slashes as delimiters or trailing flags. Make sure to escape 
               any backslashes that appear in your regex.
            </arg>
            <arg type="String" name="asCaseSentinel">
               A string used to guard against Papyrus mangling the capitalization of characters 
               in the regex. This string must have the same number of code points as the regex 
               string. Any code point that should be lowercase in the regex should be a '0' in 
               this string; code points that should be uppercase in the regex should be '1' in 
               this string. Code points that aren't case-insensitive letters can be represented 
               in this string using any other glyph. Make sure not to get confused by escaped 
               backslashes in the regex.
            </arg>
            <arg type="String" name="asReplaceWith">
               What to replace the found substring with.
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Replaces substrings based on a regex.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function performs a regular expression replace on a string and returns the 
               result.
            </p>
         </description>
         <example-data>
            <comment>
               Change the Chinese text "There are seven days in a week" to 
               "There are seven days in a year."
            </comment>
            <call return-var="sMatches" line-breaks="yes">
               <arg value="一周有七天。" />
               <arg value="周" />
               <arg value="-" />
               <arg value="年" />
            </call>
            <comment>
               Or more simply: "ABC 123 DEF" to "ABC ### DEF"
            </comment>
            <call return-var="sMatches" line-breaks="yes">
               <arg value="ABC 123 DEF" />
               <arg value="\d" />
               <arg value="-0" />
               <arg value="#" />
            </call>
         </example-data>
         <related type="method" name="RegexMatch" />
         <related type="method" name="RegexSearch" />
      </method>
      <method name="RegexSearch" returns="Bool">
         <args>
            <arg type="String" name="asHaystack">
               The string to check for matches.
            </arg>
            <arg type="String" name="asRegex">
               The regular expression to use. Regexes are in JavaScript format, but 
               without slashes as delimiters or trailing flags. Make sure to escape 
               any backslashes that appear in your regex.
            </arg>
            <arg type="String" name="asCaseSentinel">
               A string used to guard against Papyrus mangling the capitalization of characters 
               in the regex. This string must have the same number of code points as the regex 
               string. Any code point that should be lowercase in the regex should be a '0' in 
               this string; code points that should be uppercase in the regex should be '1' in 
               this string. Code points that aren't case-insensitive letters can be represented 
               in this string using any other glyph. Make sure not to get confused by escaped 
               backslashes in the regex.
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Checks whether a string contains a given substring.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function performs a regular expression search on a string and returns True 
               if the regex matches, or False otherwise.
            </p>
         </description>
         <example-data>
            <comment>
               Check whether the Chinese text "There are seven days in a week" 
               contains the word "week."
            </comment>
            <call return-var="sMatches" line-breaks="yes">
               <arg value="一周有七天。" />
               <arg value="周" />
               <arg value="-" />
            </call>
         </example-data>
         <related type="method" name="RegexMatch" />
         <related type="method" name="RegexReplace" />
      </method>
      <method name="ToBinary" returns="String">
         <args>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiBinary">
               The number to convert.
            </arg>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiDigits" default="32">
               The number of digits to use in the resulting string. If this argument is 
               zero, negative, or larger than 32, then it will be set to 32.
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Converts an integer to a binary string representation.
         </blurb>
         <example-data>
            <comment>
               This call would return "10010":
            </comment>
            <call return-var="sBinary">
               <arg value="18" />
               <arg value="5" />
            </call>
            <comment>
               This call would return "0":
            </comment>
            <call return-var="sBinary">
               <arg value="18" />
               <arg value="1" />
            </call>
         </example-data>
         <related type="method" name="BinaryToInt32" />
         <related type="method" name="HexToInt32" />
         <related type="method" name="ToHex" />
      </method>
      <method name="ToHex" returns="String">
         <args>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiHex">
               The number to convert.
            </arg>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiDigits" default="8">
               The number of digits to use in the resulting string. If this argument is 
               zero, negative, or larger than 8, then it will be set to 8.
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Converts an integer to a hexadecimal string representation.
         </blurb>
         <example-data>
            <comment>
               This call would return "12":
            </comment>
            <call return-var="sHex">
               <arg value="18" />
               <arg value="2" />
            </call>
            <comment>
               These calls would return "FFFF":
            </comment>
            <call return-var="sHex">
               <arg value="0xFFFFFFFF" />
               <arg value="4" />
            </call>
            <call return-var="sHex">
               <arg value="-1" />
               <arg value="4" />
            </call>
         </example-data>
         <related type="method" name="BinaryToInt32" />
         <related type="method" name="HexToInt32" />
         <related type="method" name="ToBinary" />
      </method>
      <method name="Trim" returns="String">
         <args>
            <arg type="String" name="asString" />
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Trims spaces off of the start and end of the string.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function returns a copy of the input string with spaces (specifically 
               codepoint 0x32, the ASCII space) stripped from the string's start and end.
            </p>
         </description>
         <example-data>
            <comment>
               This call would return "abc" or some other string that is case-insensitively 
               equal.
            </comment>
            <call return-var="sTrimmed">
               <arg value="   abc       " />
            </call>
         </example-data>
      </method>
   </methods>
</class>