<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<class name="CobbAPIBatchMove">
   <blurb>
      Functions for moving references in bulk, optionally with a world-relative offset.
   </blurb>
   <description>
      <p>
         This API allows you to move references in bulk, optionally with a world-relative offset.
      </p>
      <p>
         To use the API, you call a function to create a BatchMove task; this function returns a 
         numeric "handle," which is like a ticket that you can exchange to access your task. Once you 
         have a handle, you can use additional functions to configure your task, and then call a final 
         function to run the task and receive results.
      </p>
      <p>
         A task can only be configured or used by the same Papyrus call stack that created it; you 
         can't pass a handle to some other part of your mod and operate on it later.
      </p>
   </description>
   <methods>
      <method name="AddOperation">
         <args>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiHandle">
               The numeric handle for a BatchMove task.
            </arg>
            <arg type="ObjectReference" name="akSubject">
               The reference to move.
            </arg>
            <arg type="ObjectReference" name="akTarget">
               The reference that <var>akSubject</var> should be moved to.
            </arg>
            <arg type="Float[]" name="afPositionOffset">
               Three floats specifying an offset from <var>akTarget</var>'s position. 
               <var>akSubject</var> will be moved to the position of <var>akTarget</var> plus this 
               offset. This argument is required, but if you don't want an offset, a quick shortcut 
               is to pass <code>new Float[3]</code>.
            </arg>
            <arg type="Float[]" name="afRotation">
               Three floats specifying the rotation that <var>akSubject</var> should be moved to.
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Queues a reference to move.
         </blurb>
      </method>
      <method name="AddOperationSpecial">
         <args>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiHandle">
               The numeric handle for a BatchMove task.
            </arg>
            <arg type="ObjectReference" name="akSubject">
               The reference to move.
            </arg>
            <arg type="ObjectReference" name="akTarget">
               The reference that <var>akSubject</var> should be moved to.
            </arg>
            <arg type="Float[]" name="afPositionOffset">
               Three floats specifying an offset from <var>akTarget</var>'s position. 
               <var>akSubject</var> will be moved to the position of <var>akTarget</var> plus this 
               offset. This argument is required, but if you don't want an offset, a quick shortcut 
               is to pass <code>new Float[3]</code>.
            </arg>
            <arg type="Float[]" name="afRotation">
               Three floats specifying the rotation that <var>akSubject</var> should be moved to.
            </arg>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiOperationType">
               <table>
                  <thead>
                     <tr>
                        <th>Value</th>
                        <th>Behavior</th>
                     </tr>
                  </thead>
                  <tbody>
                     <tr>
                        <th>0</th>
                        <td>
                           A normal operation. The subject reference is moved to the target reference, 
                           with a position offset applied as appropriate.
                        </td>
                     </tr>
                     <tr>
                        <th>1</th>
                        <td>
                           If the subject reference is a load door, its destination door's teleport 
                           marker (so, the marker on the same side as the subject) is moved instead.
                        </td>
                     </tr>
                     <tr>
                        <th>2</th>
                        <td>
                           Your specified coordinates and target are ignored. The subject reference 
                           is moved back to its editor location.
                        </td>
                     </tr>
                  </tbody>
               </table>
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Queues a reference to move.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               Queues a reference to move. The <var>aiOperationType</var> argument changes the 
               behavior of this function.
            </p>
         </description>
      </method>
      <method name="Cancel">
         <blurb>
            Aborts a BatchMove task, allowing its handle to be reused.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiHandle">
               The numeric handle for a BatchMove task.
            </arg>
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="Create" returns="Int">
         <blurb>
            Creates a BatchMove task, and returns its numeric handle.
         </blurb>
         <example-data>
            <call return-var="iHandle" />
            <raw>CobbAPIBatchMove.AddOperation(iHandle, kRefToMove, kMoveTo, new Float[3], new Float[3])</raw>
            <raw>CobbAPIBatchMove.Run(iHandle)</raw>
         </example-data>
      </method>
      <method name="Run" returns="ObjectReference[]">
         <blurb>
            Executes a BatchMove task and returns an array of the references that were 
            successfully moved.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiHandle">
               The numeric handle for a BatchMove task.
            </arg>
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="SetAlsoMoveTeleportMarkers">
         <args>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiHandle">
               The numeric handle for a BatchMove task.
            </arg>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiWhich">
               <table>
                  <thead>
                     <tr>
                        <th>Value</th>
                        <th>Behavior</th>
                     </tr>
                  </thead>
                  <tbody>
                     <tr>
                        <th>0</th>
                        <td>
                           The default. Do not modify load doors' teleport markers.
                        </td>
                     </tr>
                     <tr>
                        <th>1</th>
                        <td>
                           Move load door subjects' destinations' teleport markers (so, the markers 
                           on the subjects' side) in order to keep those markers in the same 
                           position relative to the subjects.
                        </td>
                     </tr>
                     <tr>
                        <th>2</th>
                        <td>
                           Move load doors' destinations' teleport markers: compute the offset from 
                           the load door's editor position to the marker's editor position, and 
                           maintain that exact offset from the load door's new position.
                        </td>
                     </tr>
                  </tbody>
               </table>
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Controls how a BatchMove operation handles load doors' teleport markers.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               Controls how a BatchMove operation handles load doors' teleport markers.
            </p>
         </description>
      </method>
   </methods>
</class>