<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<class name="CobbAPIDetection">
   <blurb>
      Functions for tampering with AI-controlled actors' ability to detect other actors.
   </blurb>
   <description>
      <p>
         The DetectionInterceptService allows you to tamper with the detection of any actor. You 
         can flag an actor as being unable to detect other actors, or flag the actor as undetectable 
         to other actors.
      </p>
      <p>
         The service works by associating a "string tag" with a flagged actor. In order to flag or 
         unflag an actor, you must pass in a string. This allows multiple mods to flag an actor at 
         the same time, without either mod interfering with the other; the two mods' effects just 
         overlap.
      </p>
      <h2>Persistence forms</h2>
      <p>
         When you register an actor to have its detection altered, you must also pass in a 
         "persistence form." This is so that if your mod is uninstalled and your script ceases to 
         exist, your registration can be deleted (returning the actor to normal) instead of hanging 
         around forever. The form you pass in must be from your mod, but there are otherwise no 
         restrictions; CobbAPI only stores its load order slot, so don't worry about modifying or 
         even deleting the form when updating your mod.
      </p>
      <p>
         In case you're not aware: Skyrim save files include a copy of the load order. When a save 
         file is loaded, the game uses this copy to detect and handle any changes in the load order. 
         SKSE and CobbAPI can detect load order changes in the same way, and can use this to tell 
         when the user disables or uninstalls the mod that the persistence form originally came 
         from.
      </p>
      <p>
         It is recommended that you use a form added through a Papyrus property. If you use 
         Game.GetFormFromFile to retrieve your form, that will become an obstacle for users that 
         wish to merge your mod. (This is the same reason the detection API requests a form rather 
         than an ES[LPM] filename.)
      </p>
      <h2>Service availability</h2>
      <p>
         In order to offer this functionality, CobbAPI has to patch a particular part 
         of Skyrim's code in-memory. If the patch site has already been patched by 
         another mod, then CobbAPI will defer to that other mod: the DetectionIntercept-
         Service will not function, and you will not be able to add new registrations.
      </p>
      <p>Use the ServiceIsAvailable method to check whether the service is online.</p>
      <h2>Miscellaneous details</h2>
      <p>A LeveledActor's registration will be invalidated when the actor respawns.</p>
   </description>
   <methods>
      <method name="ActorCannotBeSeen">
         <blurb>
            Returns True if the DetectionInterceptService is preventing the specified actor from 
            being detected by other actors, or False otherwise.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="Actor" name="akActor" />
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="ActorCannotSee">
         <blurb>
            Returns True if the DetectionInterceptService is preventing the specified actor from 
            detecting other actors, or False otherwise.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="Actor" name="akActor" />
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="ForceActorToBeingSeen">
         <blurb>
            This function tells the DetectionInterceptService to stop preventing an actor from 
            being detected. All string tags for that actor are invalidated.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="Actor" name="akActor" />
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="ForceActorToSeeing">
         <blurb>
            This function tells the DetectionInterceptService to stop preventing an actor from 
            detecting other actors. All string tags for that actor are invalidated.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="Actor" name="akActor" />
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="ForceTagToBeingSeen">
         <blurb>
            Stops a given string tag from affecting any actor's ability to be detected.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="String" name="asTag" />
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="ForceTagToSeeing">
         <blurb>
            Stops a given string tag from affecting any actor's ability to detect other actors.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="String" name="asTag" />
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="InvalidateTag">
         <blurb>
            Stops a given string tag from affecting any actor's ability to be detected or detect 
            others.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="String" name="asTag" />
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="PreventActorFromBeingSeen">
         <blurb>
            Prevents a given actor from being detected by any other actors.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="Actor" name="akActor" />
            <arg type="Form" name="akPersistenceForm" />
            <arg type="String" name="asTag" />
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="PreventActorFromSeeing">
         <blurb>
            Prevents a given actor from detecting any other actors.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="Actor" name="akActor" />
            <arg type="Form" name="akPersistenceForm" />
            <arg type="String" name="asTag" />
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="ReturnActorToBeingSeen">
         <blurb>
            Stops a given string tag from affecting an actor's ability to be detected.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="Actor" name="akActor" />
            <arg type="String" name="asTag" />
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="ReturnActorToSeeing">
         <blurb>
            Stops a given string tag from affecting an actor's ability to detect other actors.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="Actor" name="akActor" />
            <arg type="String" name="asTag" />
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="ServiceIsAvailable">
         <blurb>
            Returns True if the DetectionInterceptService is active, functional, and accepting new 
            registrations.
         </blurb>
      </method>
   </methods>
</class>