<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<class name="CobbAPIBatchSetMotionType">
   <blurb>
      Functions for modifying the physics of references in bulk.
   </blurb>
   <description>
      <p>
         This API allows you to modify the physics behavior for a group of references.
      </p>
      <p>
         To use the API, you call a function to create a BatchSetMotionType task; this function returns a 
         numeric "handle," which is like a ticket that you can exchange to access your task. Once you 
         have a handle, you can use additional functions to configure your task, and then call a final 
         function to run the task and receive results.
      </p>
      <p>
         A task can only be configured or used by the same Papyrus call stack that created it; you 
         can't pass a handle to some other part of your mod and operate on it later. If the call stack 
         runs to completion without actually using or canceling its task handle, that handle will be 
         cleaned up when the game is next saved or loaded.
      </p>
   </description>
   <concepts>
      <concept name="Changeflags" page="Changeflags" />
   </concepts>
   <methods>
      <method name="AddOperation">
         <args>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiHandle">
               The numeric handle for a BatchSetMotionType task.
            </arg>
            <arg type="ObjectReference" name="akSubject">
               The reference to move.
            </arg>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiMotionType">
               The motion type to set.
            </arg>
            <arg type="Bool" name="abAllowActivate">
               If this argument is True, then an object set to dynamic physics will begin simulating 
               right away. If this argument is set to False, then the object will not begin its 
               physics simulation until it is touched, attacked, or Z-keyed.
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Queues a reference to have its physics changed.
         </blurb>
      </method>
      <method name="Cancel">
         <blurb>
            Aborts a BatchSetMotionType task, allowing its handle to be reused.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiHandle">
               The numeric handle for a BatchSetMotionType task.
            </arg>
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="Create" returns="Int">
         <blurb>
            Creates a BatchSetMotionType task, and returns its numeric handle.
         </blurb>
      </method>
      <method name="Run" returns="ObjectReference[]">
         <blurb>
            Executes a BatchSetMotionType task and returns an array of the references that were 
            successfully altered.
         </blurb>
         <args>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiHandle">
               The numeric handle for a BatchSetMotionType task.
            </arg>
         </args>
      </method>
      <method name="SetWhetherMarkChanged">
         <args>
            <arg type="Int" name="aiHandle">
               The numeric handle for a BatchSetMotionType task.
            </arg>
            <arg type="Bool" name="abMarkChanged" />
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Control whether affected references have their internal "change flag" for physics 
            set.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function controls whether references affected by the task have their internal 
               "change flag" for physics set. The default is to set the flag.
            </p>
         </description>
      </method>
   </methods>
</class>