<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<class name="CobbAPIForm">
   <blurb>
      Functions for working with forms in general.
   </blurb>
   <methods>
      <method name="GetBounds" returns="Int[]">
         <args>
            <arg type="Form" name="akSubject" />
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Returns an array of the form's bounds.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function returns an array of the form's bounds, as defined in the form's 
               Object Bounds (<code>OBND</code>) data. This is the data that gets filled when 
               you right-click on a form in the Creation Kit and select "Recalc Bounds."
            </p>
            <p>
               The returned data consists of six integers, which define the 3D coordinates for a 
               "min" point and a "max" point. This is enough data to infer a full oriented 
               bounding box.
            </p>
         </description>
      </method>
      <method name="GetEditorID" returns="String">
         <args>
            <arg type="Form" name="akSubject" />
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Returns the form's editor ID.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function returns the specified form's editor ID. Note that most forms do not 
               actually load their editor IDs during gameplay.
            </p>
            <p>
               Currently, CobbAPI patches the following form types to load editor IDs when they 
               normally wouldn't:
            </p>
            <ul>
               <li>AcousticSpace</li>
               <li>ImageSpace</li>
               <li>LightingTemplate</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
         <related type="method" name="GetEditorIDs" />
      </method>
      <method name="GetEditorIDs" returns="String[]">
         <args>
            <arg type="Form[]" name="akSubjects">
               An array of forms for which editor IDs should be retrieved. If any elements in 
               this array are None, an empty string will be returned for the corresponding 
               index in the result array.
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Returns an array of editor IDs for the specified forms.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               Given an array of forms, this function returns an array of those forms' editor 
               IDs. Note that most forms do not actually load their editor IDs during gameplay; 
               refer to the documentation for GetEditorID for further information.
            </p>
         </description>
         <related type="method" name="GetEditorID" />
      </method>
      <method name="IsDefiniteItem" returns="Bool">
         <args>
            <arg type="Form" name="akSubject">
               A base form to be tested, or an ObjectReference whose base form will be tested.
            </arg>
         </args>
         <blurb>
            Returns true if the form is an item, and not a leveled item.
         </blurb>
         <description>
            <p>
               This function returns True if the form is a item, and False otherwise.
            </p>
            <p>
               Specifically, this function returns True if the form is: a scroll; a piece of 
               armor; a book; an alchemy ingredient; a misc. item; an alchemy apparatus (which 
               is an unused item type left over from Oblivion); a weapon; ammunition; a key; a 
               potion (including food); a note; a soul gem; a light that has been flagged as 
               "carryable;" or an ObjectReference whose base form is any of the preceding.
            </p>
         </description>
      </method>
   </methods>
</class>