<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<content>
   <p>
      All stats on an actor are stored as <dfn>actor values</dfn> &#8212; floating-point 
      values that can have a <dfn>base value</dfn> and <dfn>modifiers</dfn>. A stat's 
      current value is the sum of the base value and all modifiers. For the remainder of 
      this article, an "actor value" will be referred to as an "AV," in order to avoid 
      word-salad phrases like "the actor value's current value."
   </p>
   <p>
      The <dfn>permanent modifier</dfn> is a modifier to an AV's maximum value, named 
      because it doesn't expire after a time limit. Permanent modifiers come from an 
      actor's enchantments and abilities, as well as from any ModActorValue script 
      calls.
   </p>
   <p>
      The <dfn>temporary modifier</dfn> is used for temporary AV buffs and drains, such 
      as Fortify Health potions and similar.
   </p>
   <p>
      The <dfn>damage modifier</dfn> is used for damage only, and for most AVs, it can 
      only be negative. (For AVs where increases would be bad, like the delay on 
      regenerating voicepoints, damage can only be positive).
   </p>
   <p>
      The key trick with modifiers is that the game engine has to undo them manually: if 
      an enchantment or ability is removed from an actor, or if a spell is dispelled, 
      then the game will check what AVs the removed object influences, and by how much; 
      the game will then undo that change exactly. (For example, if you have an ability 
      that boosts Smithing by +10, then adding the ability increases the permanent 
      modifier for Smithing by 10, and removing the ability later decreases the modifier 
      by that same amount.) This is also the key difference between the damage modifier 
      and other modifiers: you don't need to undo damage "symmetrically" &#8212; you 
      don't need to "undo" a specific bullet wound, a specific cut, or a specific bite; 
      damage can be inflicted and healed without bothering to keep track of its source.
   </p>
   <h2>Under the hood</h2>
   <p>
      All actors store health, magicka, stamina, and voicepoints data &#8212; a base 
      value and all modifiers &#8212; at all times.
   </p>
   <p>
      For other AVs, if a given AV on an actor hasn't been changed from the value on 
      the ActorBase (or the race), then no data for that AV is stored on the actor. If 
      a base value is changed, then the game stores that base value on the actor; if 
      any of an AV's modifiers change, then all three modifiers are stored on the actor. 
      These are each stored in a data structure analogous to an <code>unordered_map</code>; 
      the actual data structure is a pair of arrays, one of AV indices and another of 
      the base value or modifiers. The former array is an array of chars, so AV indices 
      in Skyrim Classic can never exceed 254 (-1 is used in some parts of the engine as 
      a sentinel value meaning "none").
   </p>
</content>